<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on R Consortium Wordpress Integration Sandbox</title>
    <link>/blog-sandbox/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on R Consortium Wordpress Integration Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog-sandbox/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap of rOpenSci&#39;s ozunconf - October 2017 in Melbourne</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2018/01/17/recap-ropenscis-ozunconf-october-2017-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2018/01/17/recap-ropenscis-ozunconf-october-2017-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>The R Consortium was happy to be a sponsor rOpenSci’s ozunconf last October in Melbourne. You can read aboutthe “unconference” on rOpenSci’s blog and follow some of the projects begun at the event here.
Through the RUGS program, R Consortium was honored to be a sponsor for this event. If you have an smaller event you would like support for, stay tuned for the official program announcement in early 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 R Consortium Silver member representatives for Board and ISC</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/12/22/2018-r-consortium-silver-member-representatives-board-isc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/12/22/2018-r-consortium-silver-member-representatives-board-isc/</guid>
      <description>Per the R Consortium ByLaws and ISC Charter, the Silver Member class is entitled to elect individuals representative of the Silver Member class for a term starting January 1, 2018 through December 31, 2018 as follows:
 1 representative to the ISC
 1 Silver Member Board Director per every 7 Silver Members, subject to provisions 4.2 and 4.3(d) of the R Consortium ByLaws. This means the Silver Member class can elect up to 2 Board Directors representing the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap of the uRos2017 conference</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/12/20/recap-uros2017-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/12/20/recap-uros2017-conference/</guid>
      <description>Editor’s Note: This post comes from Nicoleta Caragea, uRos2017 conference organizer. uRos2017 is a conference held in November 2017 for collaboration around the use of R in Romania. Through the RUGS program, R Consortium was honored to be a sponsor for this event. If you have an smaller event you would like support for, stay tuned for the official program announcement in early 2018.
uRos2017 conference
 The International Conference New Challenges for Statistical Software - The Use of R in Official Statistics - uRos2017, the fifth in a series of events, organized at Romanian NIS dedicated to the use of R Project in Romania, was held between 6-7 of November 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISC PROPOSAL SUBMISSION FAILURE</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/09/18/isc-proposal-submission-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/09/18/isc-proposal-submission-failure/</guid>
      <description>by Joseph Rickert
The ISC has determined that an error in the ISC proposal submission process has caused us to lose some, but not all proposals. If you submitted a project proposal to the ISC and have received a confirmation email then you are fine. However, if you have not received a confirmation email, please email your proposal as a pdf attachment to proposal@r-consortium.org
If you do not receive a confirmation within 24 hours please email hadley@rstudio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Consortium Call for Proposals: Summer 2017</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/08/11/r-consortium-call-for-proposals-summer-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/08/11/r-consortium-call-for-proposals-summer-2017/</guid>
      <description>by Joseph Rickert and Hadley Wickham
The second and final ISC Call for Proposals for 2017 is now open. In this round, with the intention of spreading the available funds as widely as possible, the ISC is encouraging the R community to submit proposals for projects that are smaller in scope than those solicited earlier this year. For this round, the total funds requested for an individual grant should be less than $10,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take the R Consortium&#39;s Survey on R!</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/06/29/take-the-r-consortiums-survey-on-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/06/29/take-the-r-consortiums-survey-on-r/</guid>
      <description>by Joseph Rickert and Hadley Wickham
Help us keep the conversation going: Take the R Consortium’s Survey. Let us know: What are you thinking? What do you make of the way R is developing? How do you use R? What is important to you? How could life be better? What issues should we be addressing? What does the big picture look like? We are looking for a few clues and we would like to hear from the entire R Community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Coverage Tool for R Working Group Achieves First Release</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/06/28/code-coverage-tool-for-r-working-group-achieves-first-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/06/28/code-coverage-tool-for-r-working-group-achieves-first-release/</guid>
      <description>by Mark Hornick, Code Coverage Working Group Leader
The “Code Coverage Tool for R” project, proposed by Oracle and approved by the R Consortium Infrastructure Steering Committee, started just over a year ago. Project goals included providing an enhanced tool that determines code coverage upon execution of a test suite, and leveraging such a tool more broadly as part of the R ecosystem.
What is code coverage?
As defined in Wikipedia, “code coverage is a measure used to describe the degree to which the source code of a program is executed when a particular test suite runs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving DBI: A Retrospect</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/05/15/improving-dbi-a-retrospect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/05/15/improving-dbi-a-retrospect/</guid>
      <description>by Kirill Müller
The “Improving DBI” project, funded by the R consortium and started about a year ago includes the definition and implementation of a testable specification for DBI and making RSQLite fully compliant to the new specification. Besides the established DBI and RSQLite packages, I have spent a lot of time on the new DBItest package. Final updates to these packages will be pushed to CRAN at the end of May.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q1 2017 ISC Grants</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/04/03/q1-2017-isc-grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/04/03/q1-2017-isc-grants/</guid>
      <description>by Hadley Wickham and Joseph Rickert
The Infrastructure Steering Committee (ISC) was very pleased with both the quantity and quality of proposals received during the recent round of funding which closed on February 10th. Funding decisions were difficult. In the end, the ISC awarded grants to ten of the twenty-seven proposals it received for a total award of $234,000. Here is a brief summary of the projects that received awards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISC Project Status Webinar</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/01/24/isc-project-status-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/01/24/isc-project-status-webinar/</guid>
      <description>Join us for a webinar on Jan 31, 2017 at 9:30 AM PST.
[button color=“see-through-1” hover_text_color_override=“#fff” size=“large” url=“https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/recording/4493833045968682243” text=“View Recording” color_override=“”]
Hear about R Consortium activities by watching the first ISC Project Status Webinar held on Tuesday, January 31st at 9:30AM PST (5:30PM GMT), 2017. Join us for 5 minute lightning talks on each active R Consortium project including:
 R Hub - Gabor Csárdi
   SatRdays -Gergely Daroczi</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation Joins R Consortium to Encourage Development, Maintenance and Distribution of R Software</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/01/11/gordon-and-betty-moore-foundation-joins-r-consortium-to-encourage-development-maintenance-and-distribution-of-r-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/01/11/gordon-and-betty-moore-foundation-joins-r-consortium-to-encourage-development-maintenance-and-distribution-of-r-software/</guid>
      <description>Grant is a part of the Moore Foundation’s Data-Driven Discovery Initiative to support data scientists 
SAN FRANCISCO – [Jan 11, 2017, 10:00 ET] – The R Consortium, an open source foundation supporting the R user community and a Linux Foundation project, today welcomed the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation to the Consortium as a supporting Platinum member. The Moore Foundation grant will enable the R Consortium to expand its support for the community developing, maintaining, distributing and using the R programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Features Now on CRAN</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2017/01/03/simple-features-now-on-cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2017/01/03/simple-features-now-on-cran/</guid>
      <description>by Edzer Pebesma
Support for handling and analyzing spatial data in R goes back a long way. In 2003, a group of package developers sat together and decided to adopt a shared understanding of how spatial data should be organized in R. This led to the development of the package sp and its helper packages rgdal and rgeos. sp offers simple classes for points, lines, polygons and grids, which may be associated with further properties (attributes), and takes care of coordinate reference systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Proposals</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/12/06/call-for-proposals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/12/06/call-for-proposals/</guid>
      <description>by Hadley Wickham
The infrastructure Steering Committee (ISC) is pleased to announce that the committee is now ready to accept proposals for the first round of funding in 2017. The ISC is broadly interested in projects that will make a difference to the R community. Don’t be afraid to think big! We have the budget to fund ambitious projects and we want to fund infrastructure that can help large segments of the R community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halfway through &#34;Improving DBI&#34;</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/12/05/halfway-through-improving-dbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/12/05/halfway-through-improving-dbi/</guid>
      <description>by Kirill Müller
In early 2016 the R Consortium partially accepted my “Improving DBI” proposal. An important part is the design and implementation of a testable DBI specification. Initially I also proposed to make three DBI backends to open-source databases engines (RSQLite, RMySQL, and RPostgres) compatible to the new DBI specification, but funding allows to work on only one DBI backend. I chose RSQLite for a number of reasons:
 It is a very important package, judging by the number of reverse CRAN and Bioconductor dependencies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RL10N hits its first milestone</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/11/22/rl10n-hits-its-first-milestone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/11/22/rl10n-hits-its-first-milestone/</guid>
      <description>by Richard Cotton and Thomas Leeper
richie_logo
 R is gradually taking over the world (of data analysis). However, proficiency in English remains a prerequisite for effectively working with R. While R has a system for translating messages, warnings, and error messages into other languages, very few packages take advantage of this functionality.
Part of the problem is that it currently takes a lot of effort to create translations. There are a few issues that the RL10N project aims to address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing RC RUGS: R Consortium R User Group Support Program</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/11/03/introducing-rugs-r-consortium-r-user-group-support-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/11/03/introducing-rugs-r-consortium-r-user-group-support-program/</guid>
      <description>The R Consortium is very happy to announce RC RUGS, the R Consortium R User Group Support Program. We believe that user groups are a great strength of the R Community and we would like to do all that we can to encourage the formation of new user groups and to help existing R user groups flourish.
The 2016/2017 RC RUGS program provides financial support for R User Groups based on their size and the frequency with which they meet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at Watson DevCon November 9 – 10</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/10/17/join-us-at-watson-devcon-november-9-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/10/17/join-us-at-watson-devcon-november-9-10/</guid>
      <description>Join us, November 9-10 at the Watson Developer Conference (R Consortium is co-sponsoring the event), at the Innovation Hangar in SanFrancisco, CA, for an opportunity to learn about the latest Watson technologies. Also meet some of the Watson teams and partners who are building with cognitive, real-time.
This event will give you everything you need to build and learn about Watson. From weekend hacker to seasoned app builder, the conference is designed to have a little bit of something for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Hub - Public Beta</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/10/11/r-hub-public-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/10/11/r-hub-public-beta/</guid>
      <description>[vc_row type=“in_container” full_screen_row_position=“middle” scene_position=“center” text_color=“dark” text_align=“left” overlay_strength=“0.3”][vc_column column_padding=“no-extra-padding” column_padding_position=“all” background_color_opacity=“1” background_hover_color_opacity=“1” width=“1/1” tablet_text_alignment=“default” phone_text_alignment=“default”][vc_column_text]R Hub - Public Beta Oct 25, 2016 9:00 AM - 10:00 AM PDT
R-HUB, the most significant project that the R Consortium has funded to date, is making progress. The major goal of R-Hub is to develop a modern platform for simplifying and improving the R package development process. It will provide facilities to assist package creation, building binaries, and for publishing, distributing and maintaining packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esri joins the R Consortium</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/09/26/esri-joins-the-r-consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/09/26/esri-joins-the-r-consortium/</guid>
      <description>In another sign of R’s push into the enterprise, leading GIS vendor Esri has joined the R Consortium, adding to a roster of tech companies that includes Microsoft, IBM, Oracle and Google.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The start of satRdays</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/09/07/the-start-of-satrdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/09/07/the-start-of-satrdays/</guid>
      <description>[vc_row type=“in_container” full_screen_row_position=“middle” scene_position=“center” text_color=“dark” text_align=“left” overlay_strength=“0.3”][vc_column column_padding=“no-extra-padding” column_padding_position=“all” background_color_opacity=“1” background_hover_color_opacity=“1” width=“1/1” tablet_text_alignment=“default” phone_text_alignment=“default”][vc_column_text]by Gergely Daroczi, organizer
Almost 200 people from 19 countries registered for the first satRday conference which was held last Saturday, September 3rd, in Budapest. The final count showed that nearly 170 R users spent 12 hours at the conference venue attending workshops, regular and lighting talks, social events and a data visualization challenge. If you missed the event, you can rewatch the live stream of the conference talks at any time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The R Consortium Funds Three Projects in July</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/08/22/the-r-consortium-funds-three-projects-in-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/08/22/the-r-consortium-funds-three-projects-in-july/</guid>
      <description>[vc_row type=“in_container” full_screen_row_position=“middle” scene_position=“center” text_color=“dark” text_align=“left” overlay_strength=“0.3”][vc_column column_padding=“no-extra-padding” column_padding_position=“all” background_color_opacity=“1” background_hover_color_opacity=“1” width=“1/1” tablet_text_alignment=“default” phone_text_alignment=“default”][vc_column_text]
by Joseph Rickert and Hadley Wickham
The Infrastructure Steering Committee (ISC) has approved funding for three of the thirteen proposed projects received during the most recent round of contributed proposals which closed on July 10th. The total amount awarded was just over $29,000. A brief description of each of these projects follows.
The R Documentation Task Force: The Next Generation R Documentation System Andrew Redd received $10,000 to lead a new ISC working group, The R Documentation Task Force, which has a mission to design and build the next generation R documentation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Insider Australia: Lean any 11 of these programming languages and you&#39;ll always have a job</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/06/26/business-insider-australia-lean-any-11-of-these-programming-languages-and-youll-always-have-a-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/06/26/business-insider-australia-lean-any-11-of-these-programming-languages-and-youll-always-have-a-job/</guid>
      <description>There are thousands of programming languages, but some of them are far more popular than others.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InfoWorld: Beginner&#39;s Guide to R</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/06/26/infoworld-beginners-guide-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/06/26/infoworld-beginners-guide-to-r/</guid>
      <description>Interest in the R statistics language is soaring, especially for data analysis. Get to know this hot programming option in our beginner’s guide.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Public Version of the r-hub Builder</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/06/06/first-public-version-of-the-r-hub-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/06/06/first-public-version-of-the-r-hub-builder/</guid>
      <description>[vc_row type=“in_container” full_screen_row_position=“middle” scene_position=“center” text_color=“dark” text_align=“left” overlay_strength=“0.3”][vc_column column_padding=“no-extra-padding” column_padding_position=“all” background_color_opacity=“1” background_hover_color_opacity=“1” width=“1/1” tablet_text_alignment=“default” phone_text_alignment=“default”][vc_column_text]
The r-hub builder is the first major project of the R consortium. It is an R package build and continuous integration service, open to all members of the R community.
Goals for R-Hub include:
 simplify the R package development process: creating a package, building binaries and continuous integration, publishing, distributing and maintaining it;
 encourage community contributions; and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Invests in R Programming Language for Data Science; Joins R Consortium</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/06/06/ibm-invests-in-r-programming-language-for-data-science-joins-r-consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/06/06/ibm-invests-in-r-programming-language-for-data-science-joins-r-consortium/</guid>
      <description>Signals commitment to open source to help improve data analysis and address growing demands of big data
SAN FRANCISCO (Spark Summit) June 6, 2016 – The R Consortium, an open source foundation to support the R user community and a Linux Foundation project, today is announcing IBM is becoming a Platinum member of the project, which demonstrates a significant investment in the open source R programming language to simplify data analysis and statistical computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast Company: Why the R programming language is good for business</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/05/26/fast-company-why-the-r-programming-language-is-good-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/05/26/fast-company-why-the-r-programming-language-is-good-for-business/</guid>
      <description>With terabytes of data at hand, every business is trying to figure out the best way to understand information about their customers and themselves.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FierceBigData: R Consortium funds initiatives to advance R language</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/03/28/fiercebigdata-r-consortium-funds-initiatives-to-advance-r-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/03/28/fiercebigdata-r-consortium-funds-initiatives-to-advance-r-language/</guid>
      <description>The R Consortium, which is an independent open source foundation that supports the R community and a Linux Foundation project, announced this morning that it is funding seven community projects and the formation of two technical working groups to further advance the R language. READ MORE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Consortium Funds Technical Initiatives, Community Events and Training to Support R User Community</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/03/23/r-consortium-funds-technical-initiatives-community-events-and-training-to-support-r-user-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/03/23/r-consortium-funds-technical-initiatives-community-events-and-training-to-support-r-user-community/</guid>
      <description>_ R Consortium awards seven grant recipients and forms two working groups to advance R programming language_
SAN FRANCISCO – March 23, 2016 – The R Consortium, an open source foundation to support the R user community and a Linux Foundation project, today is announcing funding for seven community projects and the formation of two technical working groups. These milestones advance the R Consortium’s mission to support the R community through the identification, development and implementation of infrastructure projects that drive standards and best practices for R code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Consortium Outlook 2016</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2016/03/11/r-consortium-outlook-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2016/03/11/r-consortium-outlook-2016/</guid>
      <description>[vc_row type=“in_container” full_screen_row_position=“middle” scene_position=“center” text_color=“dark” text_align=“left” overlay_strength=“0.3”][vc_column column_padding=“no-extra-padding” column_padding_position=“all” background_color_opacity=“1” background_hover_color_opacity=“1” width=“1/1” tablet_text_alignment=“default” phone_text_alignment=“default”][vc_column_text]2016 is already shaping up to be another banner year for the R Project. The project is as active as ever, with the new R 3.2.4 just released (and R 3.3.0 following up very soon), and the milestone of 8,000 contributed packages was passed just last month (coincidentally, on the 16th anniversary of the release of R 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer World: New $85K package development service backed by R Consortium</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/computer-world-new-85k-package-development-service-backed-by-r-consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/computer-world-new-85k-package-development-service-backed-by-r-consortium/</guid>
      <description>R-Hub is the first project backed by the Infrastructure Steering Committee; more grant money now available. READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FierceBigData: R-Hub awarded first R Consortium grant</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/fiercebigdata-r-hub-awarded-first-r-consortium-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/fiercebigdata-r-hub-awarded-first-r-consortium-grant/</guid>
      <description>R-Hub, a developing, building, testing and R packages validation service, is the recipient of the first ever R Consortium grant.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Consortium Awards First Grant to Help Advance Popular Programming Language for Unlocking Value from Data</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/r-consortium-awards-first-grant-to-help-advance-popular-programming-language-for-unlocking-value-from-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/r-consortium-awards-first-grant-to-help-advance-popular-programming-language-for-unlocking-value-from-data/</guid>
      <description>SAN FRANCISCO and BOSTON (EARL Conference), November 2, 2015 – The R Consortium, a Linux Foundation Collaborative Project and open source foundation to support the R user community, today announced it is awarding its first grant to advance the infrastructure supporting the R programming language. Led by the R Consortium Infrastructure Steering Committee (ISC), the grant program provides financial support to projects that will address critical needs of the R user community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SD Times Digest: R Consortium announces first grant</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/sd-times-digest-r-consortium-announces-first-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/sd-times-digest-r-consortium-announces-first-grant/</guid>
      <description>The R Consortium has announced its first grant will go to a new service designed for developing, building, testing and validating R packages.READ MORE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The VAR Guy: Open Source R Code to Get New Hub with Help from the Linux Foundation</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/the-var-guy-open-source-r-code-to-get-new-hub-with-help-from-the-linux-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/11/02/the-var-guy-open-source-r-code-to-get-new-hub-with-help-from-the-linux-foundation/</guid>
      <description>The R Consortium and the Linux Foundation will fund a new open source developer hub for the R programming language called R-Hub, which complements CRAN and R-Forge. READ MORE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Consortium Infrastructure Steering Committee (ISC) elects Chair</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/09/24/r-consortium-infrastructure-steering-committee-isc-elects-chair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/09/24/r-consortium-infrastructure-steering-committee-isc-elects-chair/</guid>
      <description>[vc_row type=“in_container” full_screen_row_position=“middle” scene_position=“center” text_color=“dark” text_align=“left” overlay_strength=“0.3”][vc_column column_padding=“no-extra-padding” column_padding_position=“all” background_color_opacity=“1” background_hover_color_opacity=“1” width=“1/1” tablet_text_alignment=“default” phone_text_alignment=“default”][vc_column_text]by Joseph Rickert
This week, the Infrastructure Steering Committee (ISC) of the R Consortium unanimously elected Hadley Wickham as its chair thereby also giving Hadley a seat on the R Consortium board of directors. Congratulations Hadley!!
This is a major step forward towards putting the R Consortium in business. Not only is the ISC the group that will decide on what projects the R Consortium will undertake, but it will also be responsible for actually getting the work done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Using R Securely</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/08/17/best-practices-for-using-r-securely/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/08/17/best-practices-for-using-r-securely/</guid>
      <description>[vc_row type=“in_container” full_screen_row_position=“middle” scene_position=“center” text_color=“dark” text_align=“left” overlay_strength=“0.3”][vc_column column_padding=“no-extra-padding” column_padding_position=“all” background_color_opacity=“1” background_hover_color_opacity=“1” width=“1/1” tablet_text_alignment=“default” phone_text_alignment=“default”][vc_column_text]The R Consortium was formed to serve the interests of the R user community, and to that end the members of the R Consortium would like to share some best practices for using R securely and safely. These recommendations are not unique to R: you should follow similar practices for any software you download from the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The R Consortium Begins its Mission</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/08/13/the-r-consortium-begins-its-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/08/13/the-r-consortium-begins-its-mission/</guid>
      <description>[vc_row type=“in_container” full_screen_row_position=“middle” scene_position=“center” text_color=“dark” text_align=“left” overlay_strength=“0.3”][vc_column column_padding=“no-extra-padding” column_padding_position=“all” background_color_opacity=“1” background_hover_color_opacity=“1” width=“1/1” tablet_text_alignment=“default” phone_text_alignment=“default”][vc_column_text]Since the announcement of the R Consortium on June 30, the members of the Consortium have begun the mission of supporting the R project and the vast community of R users around the world. The first task was to appoint members of the Board of the R Consortium, and to that end we are pleased to announce the following board members:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datanami: Consortium Makes Business Case For R Language</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/30/datanami-consortium-makes-business-case-for-r-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/30/datanami-consortium-makes-business-case-for-r-language/</guid>
      <description>As more data scientists and researchers embrace the R programming language and statistical computing environment, the Linux Foundation has moved to strengthen the user community and, with it, the development of more business applications through a collaborative development initiative called the R Consortium.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Foundation Announces R Consortium to Support Millions of Users Around the World</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/30/linux-foundation-announces-r-consortium-to-support-millions-of-users-around-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/30/linux-foundation-announces-r-consortium-to-support-millions-of-users-around-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists from industry and academic research will work together to advance world’s most popular language for analytics and data science and support the rapid growth of the R user community SAN FRANCISCO, Calif., June 30, 2015 – The Linux Foundation, the nonprofit organization dedicated to accelerating the growth of Linux and collaborative development, today announced the R Consortium. This new organization will strengthen both the technical and user communities as a Collaborative Project hosted at Linux Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VentureBeat: Microsoft, Oracle, HP, Tibco, RStudio form the R Consortium under the Linux Foundation</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/30/venturebeat-microsoft-oracle-hp-tibco-rstudio-form-the-r-consortium-under-the-linux-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/30/venturebeat-microsoft-oracle-hp-tibco-rstudio-form-the-r-consortium-under-the-linux-foundation/</guid>
      <description>The nonprofit Linux Foundation today announced a new initiative called the R Consortium, a new group to unite the users of the open-source R programming language, which is widely used among data scientists and statisticians.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ComputerWorld: Google, Microsoft, Oracle back new R Consortium at Linux Foundation</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/29/computerworld-google-microsoft-oracle-back-new-r-consortium-at-linux-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/29/computerworld-google-microsoft-oracle-back-new-r-consortium-at-linux-foundation/</guid>
      <description>As foreshadowed on Twitter yesterday, a new R Consortium of major vendors launched today aimed at “strengthen[ing] both the technical and user communities,” according to a Linux Foundation announcement.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolution Analytics: R Consortium News Roundup</title>
      <link>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/06/revolution-analytics-r-consortium-news-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog-sandbox/2015/06/06/revolution-analytics-r-consortium-news-roundup/</guid>
      <description>In case you missed the news last week, the R Consortium was announced. This new non-profit trade group will work with the R Foundation to support the R Community and the R Project generally.
READ MORE</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>